<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Engineers Without Borders</title>
 <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//"/>
 <updated>2015-04-30T17:07:59-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Joseph Milla</name>
   <email>jmilla@acm.org</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Guatemala Trip</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/02/17/guatemala-trip/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/02/17/guatemala-trip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Photo set from the Guatemala Trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_0001.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_0002.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_7705.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_8015.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_7949.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_0003.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing 2015 Board Members</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/01/19/introducing-2015-board/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/01/19/introducing-2015-board</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;president&quot;&gt;President&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayzvara Suntharalingam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vice-president&quot;&gt;Vice President&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda Sopkin, Arjun Kumar, Kevin Ger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;treasurer&quot;&gt;Treasurer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Wu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-officers&quot;&gt;Information Officers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Dixon, Hunter Smith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;events-officer&quot;&gt;Events Officer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Lin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;webmaster&quot;&gt;Webmaster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Milla&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EWB Banquet</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/12/13/ewb-banquet/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/12/13/ewb-banquet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The annual year-end banquet and awards ceremony was held on the 10th of December at the University YMCA. Both members and mentors alike had the opportunity to reflect on our progress and accomplishments this past year. The upcoming board was introduced, outstanding members &amp;amp; project leads acknowledged, while our graduating seniors were given a farewell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Travel Panel</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/11/22/travel-panel/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/11/22/travel-panel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our general meeting was hosted on Tuesday November 18th at 6:00-7:00pm in MSEB100! We discussed about the general traveling process with regards to our international projects. Older members were able to share their personal experiences with newer members.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EWB National Conference</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/11/08/ewb-national-conference/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/11/08/ewb-national-conference</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The annual conference was hosted during the 31st October to 2nd November in Reston, Virginia! Participants managed to learn from informational sessions and insightful speakers regarding international development and service learning topics. Additionally, the conference provided participants with a great opportunity to network with corporate representatives, professionals and students alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Program Application</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/10/11/new-program-application/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/10/11/new-program-application</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our chapter is preparing to get involved with two additional projects that are both locally and globally orientated. Interested candidates that submitted applications were chosen through a rigorous selection process for both the domestic and international projects on offer. We wish the upcoming teams all the best in their preparations for the new projects!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Member Orientation</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/09/20/new-member-orientation/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/09/20/new-member-orientation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our chapter hosted an orientation session to integrate new members with various projects. We hope that newer members are able to adapt to our on-going projects and get exposed to important elements &amp;amp; skill sets needed to succeed in a project. Project leads coordinated hands-on activities to convey information on their respective projects and help new members transition smoothly!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Info Session</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/09/13/info-session/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/09/13/info-session</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two informational sessions were  hosted on the 9th and 10th of September respectively in DCL1320 to share about what we do as a chapter and how members could get involved in various international development projects available in our chapter. We were glad that affliated organizations were able to participate in the event as well to expose attendees to the opportunities beyond EWB!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assessment Trip</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/08/01/assessment-trip/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/08/01/assessment-trip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0002.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our most recent assessment trip last August was extremely successful. During the trip, we surveyed the village households in order to gain a complete understanding of the people’s needs and expectations for this project. We also asked questions pertaining to the financial sustainability of the project. Unanimously, the people of the Likoko village said that they could afford the monthly utility bills that would come out of establishing an electric grid system. In addition to the house surveys, we created a Memorandum of Understanding and an Implementation Agreement that the village leaders agreed and signed. In these documents, the community leaders confirmed that they would be able to supply a 10% cash contribution towards the initial construction costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0001.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0003.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, during their trip, the project team met with the Mayor of Buea. He gave his blessing for the project and promised to supply government-run street lights for the municipality. Overall, there is an overwhelming support in the community for this project to go forward so we expect there to be high community involvement throughout the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0206.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0435.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also investigated financial considerations for the project during this trip. We were able to get price estimates for installing in-house wiring. We surveyed possible transmission line routes and determined an ideal path that would connect all of the Likoko households as well as four schools to the power line. We are currently working on cost estimates for constructing a transmission line along this route. Lastly, we investigated potential future projects such as health education and electrically powered water distribution, which could be our next steps after implementing the electrical grid system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
