<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Engineers Without Borders</title>
 <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//"/>
 <updated>2015-09-14T18:12:13-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Joseph Milla</name>
   <email>jmilla@acm.org</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 28 Thursday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/28/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/28/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is our last morning in Ntisaw. We leave at 11 am. Marceline makes us a big breakfast of spaghetti eggs and bread. She baked us an extra loaf to take in the car with us. I can’t believe that this week has gone so fast. I had such an incredible time and it is bittersweet to leave. I am looking forward to seeing my friends and family and to starting my internship in a week. But I will miss the mountains, the laidback lifestyle, and the people. Especially my team members, I have spent every waking moment of the last 10 days with them and I expect I will go though a bit of separation anxiety when I have to leave them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I am so thankful that I was given this opportunity. Traveling to Cameroon has been my dream ever since high school when I saw the EWB table at the engineering open house. I am so glad that I had the chance to work internationally and develop personal and engineering skills. There aren’t too many twenty year olds who are given that experience and I loved every second of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped shove our duffle bags and hiking backpacks into the back of the bush taxi and hugged everyone who had gathered goodbye. I squeezed myself into the backseat with a bag on my lap and waited for the car to pull away. When it did I waved and couldn’t help but look back. But afterwards I set my gaze forward excited for all of the possibilities and dreams that would come my way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 27 Wednesday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/27/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/27/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is our last full day in the village and the first thing we did was have a water committee meeting.  Our goal was to reassure the community and do damage control from the discussion the previous day. The first thing that we explained was that we were still doing work with the community, and that we weren’t just dashing out on them. We explained that we were working on a solution to the exposed pipes in the rocky area, as well as we were creating a design for a new Circfa tank. You could tell by the looks on their faces that this alone made them feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly we had them discuss if there were any other problems with the system. After a long discussion they realized that all of the other problems that they had, they had the knowledge to fix. The water committee started to realize that the maintenance team did have a good handle on the system. We finished by explaining that our group was a water project, and that limited what we could do. We understood their desire for stoves and electricity but that for them to receive these things they would have to go though EWB USA and apply for a new project. The committee was reassured that it was not our decision to leave them, but that it was our responsibility to pass the torch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this long meeting I spent the rest of the afternoon playing with the children. We all went to the front yard of Pastor Julius’ house and they taught me how to do a headstand while I taught them how to do a one handed cartwheel.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 26 Tuesday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/26/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/26/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/DSCN0156.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning Marceline made us French toast for breakfast, it was amazing. Afterwards our team went to the government school to teach those students the five senses lesson. It went even better there because those students have a better understanding of English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/DSCN0250.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/IMG_7427.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This afternoon we had our big celebration to celebrate the collaboration of our group and the community.  The party began with a village meeting. Zac started off the meeting by explaining how we were so impressed with the village and how much ownership they have taken in their system. We expressed that it was getting to the point that they knew more about their system than we did. And that our responsibilities would become less and less. Julius as always translated for us, but something must have gotten lost in the translation, because the entire village started getting upset thinking that we were leaving them without a second thought. One after one people stood up and expressed their feelings of sadness and even betrayal that we were leaving them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/IMG_7432.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not something that we were expecting and we knew that we would have to fix these feelings before we left. After eating lunch with the village and taking pictures with all of them, our team went on a long walk to discuss how to face this new problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 25 Monday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/25/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/25/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning we started off the day by having another women’s meeting. With them we discussed the library as well as the problem of the high iron content. The biggest thing that we wanted to ensure was that the water from the taps, although less appealing, was still safer to drink than the water from the stream. We helped them understand that iron is a type two contaminant and that it has no negative health effects, if anything a little bit of iron can be good for a woman’s health.  However, our system has more than a little bit of iron so we discussed with them the solutions that we have to reduce it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I went to the Islamic school with a few of our team members to teach a lesson. As education lead for our team, I was completely in charge. My main goal for the lesson was to teach a bit of English as well as make the learning fun for the children. Ntisaw has a problem with children not wanting to continue with higher education because education is not seen as something necessary there. I know that I cannot change their lives with one lesson, but if I could I would want them to enjoy learning and have a passion to continue with their education.  However, these children are ages six to twelve and with the addition of the language barrier I really only have their attention for twenty minutes. Because of that I chose a simple lesson of the five senses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the lesson was touch, passing around felt and sandpaper. Then I talked about smell and had them smell two vials, one with water the other with spice. For sound I played my harmonica and did a clapping exercise. For taste they all got a piece of candy. And for sight they experienced the different colors by drawling on a five senses coloring sheet. We finished off the lesson by teaching them a short song about the five senses. All in all, I think that the lesson went well. The kids all learned a few more words of English and spent the rest of the day singing the song that we had taught them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 24 Sunday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/24/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/24/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/IMG_6987.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning we had a traditional breakfast of puff puffs (deep fried dough balls) and nutella. It was delicious. Afterwards we got ready for a long day in the rocky area to do water sampling and testing. However, when we began our testing we realized that our bacteria plates were all contaminated. They had become damaged during our fight over and were now basically useless. We had a problem and needed to start doing some serious problem solving to fix it.  Our mentor Ann mentioned that she had a friend who worked in DNA testing and we decided that that would be our best shot. So we filled up some sample bottles to bring back home to the states for testing.  Unfortunately our only plan for the day was to do the bacteria testing, so we spent the rest of our time relaxing with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 23 Saturday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/23/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/23/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/IMG_6958.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning we tried to have a water committee meeting. We met at the water chairman’s home however we did not have enough attendance so we went home. This village is helping me learn more about patience. I am realizing that if a meeting doesn’t work one day, you must keep trying until you succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we went for a long hike to see a waterfall. The waterfall is called Kofatar. It translates to the son gives to the father. The waterfall is made up of three separate waterfalls, the son a short heavy waterfall, the mother a long spidery fall and the father the largest waterfall of them all. It was great to learn about the history of the falls and the people who had first settled there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our adventure, the rain set in fast and hard. That is another thing about Ntisaw that I am starting to appreciate. When the rain comes everything else stops. All you can do is rush indoors and wait for it to be over. We have a few of the village children in our home with us so we teach them how to play Uno. We spend the rest of the afternoon laughing and listening to the rain pound on the tin roof.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 22 Friday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/22/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/22/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/IMG_6990.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning we started off the day with a village meeting. At all of these meetings we use Pastor Julius as our translator. The Water Chairman started of the meeting saying that it was a very busy day and that they would keep the meeting short. Afterwards that made me laugh because the meeting lasted three hours. It was an interesting experience to sit there during the meeting in a place of honor and yet feel so separate from it. They all discussed for a few hours until we finally had a chance to speak. But that entire time previous we didn’t have a clue what they were saying. They best we could do was to try to read what people were saying by their tone and body language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the meeting we discussed private taps, maintenance problems, key holders, the celebration that we were planning, and the developing library. All in all, the meeting went well and afterwards we went to Salema to discuss many of the same things with the women of the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now I am starting to understand how things go differently here. The village follows a different sort of clock. Everything is a bit slower and laid back. People often arrive an hour late to meetings. However, you must make it clear to arrive on American time if you do want them to arrive on time. I am beginning to enjoy the way it is done here; it is acceptable to get a bit less done in a day.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 21 Thursday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/21/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/21/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/05/IMG_7039.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Bailey Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I learned quite a bit about water quality testing. Before I woke up Nora was already working. She is doing an independent research study to see how educating the community can affect their personal water reserves. While she was in Ntisaw last spring she taught lessons on how to collect and store water in clean buckets to reduce contamination. To follow up with these lessons she is collecting water samples from people’s personal water storages. We spent the morning testing them to see how well people took Nora’s lessons to heart. I was put in charge of testing the water’s PH as well as levels of nitrites and ammonia. This was the easiest job with just a simple drop test and color chart to reference. We also spent a considerable amount of time doing bacteria testing using 3M E. coli plates.  The method is rather simple but insightful and I am glad that I now know how to use and read them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent this afternoon climbing a mountain. It was one that Nora had climbed during her semester here. It was not too much of a difficult climb, but the view was gorgeous. It is crazy how secluded we are here. There are hardly any other villages around. You look out on the horizon and see mountains rolling off into the distance. At dusk the only way to make out a village is by the little glimmer of light that reflects off of the tin roofs in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 20 Wednesday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/20/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/20/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we traveled to Ndu for National Day. National Day occurs once a year in Cameroon; it is their equivalence of Independence Day. Cameroon was originally two parts; an English colony and a French colony. National Day is the day when these two colonies united. National Day was a really cool experience. At first I was a little nervous that I would feel so out of place. In many ways I was, but that was all right. I enjoyed watching the children march in the parade. In addition, I loved watching the crowds. Everyone had dressed up in the finest for the holiday and the colors were astonishing. That is one thing I will never forget about Cameroon. Their cities are a bit undeveloped and covered in a layer of thick red dust. But the people are bright and colorful, everything from magenta to turquoise, lime to fuchsia. And their motorbikes are just as colorful as the people as they wiz by loud and proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the afternoon after the parade going shopping. It was fun to roam the streets and look for good deals. In comparison to the US the produce is very inexpensive so we buy many tomatoes, onions, and peppers. It is nearly impossible to purchase vegetables in Ntisaw so we try to buy what we will need for the rest of the week.
When we return from National Day we hold a Maintenance Team meeting. Our maintenance team members are Esau, Idrisu, and Tonku. I have heard a lot about them and it is exciting to meet them. They fill us in on how the system is doing and what repairs they have made. They also inform us the problems that they are facing. These being the high iron content in the water, the exposed pipes in the rocky area, and the vandalism of the Circfa tank.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bailey Blog, May 19 Tuesday</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/05/19/daily-baily-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/05/19/daily-baily-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is our first true day in Ntisaw, Cameroon. We arrived in the village late last night dirty and exhausted. Our cook Marceline made us some dinner, but we could hardly taste it, we were all so excited to crawl into bed. I am a bit disappointed that we arrived at night because I couldn’t get a good look at the village until this morning. However, there is something equally as magical about that. Waking up to the sound of chickens and cows and emerging to a location unlike anything that you have ever seen. The village and all of its homes are beautiful. Everything is made of red brick and the houses are topped with shiny tin roofs. It is the wet season so everything is teaming with green life. The color is so bright and creates a beautiful contrast to the red dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it is our first day in the village we do not have much planned. The biggest thing that we want to accomplish today is showing our faces to the village. To let them know that we are here and that we are looking forward to working with them. First thing in the morning we take a walk through the main road in town to say hello to people and to stop by a small shop to pick up tea. Everyone that we pass is overjoyed to see Nora. Nora is a member of our EWB group and this is her fifth trip to Ntisaw, last spring she lived in the village for five months. These people are like family to her and they are all so excited to be reunited. Everyone that we pass says good morning and asks us how we are doing with the local greeting, Wasake. They all greet us with handshakes and hugs and assure us how welcome we are in the village. Going to Ntisaw has been my dream for the past two years and I am so excited to be here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we return to Pastor Julius’ home we have a wonderful breakfast of pancakes and nutella waiting for us. We spend the rest of the morning talking to villagers and planning out the rest of the week. That afternoon we walked the water system and toured all of the water tanks. Although I had heard much about our system and tanks it solidified everything I had learned about them by seeing them in person. This walk was made much more fun by the addition of a handful of neighborhood kids. Most of the kids skipped school that day because it was our first day in the village. So everywhere we went a pack of kids went with us. And they were always eager to hold our hands. I enjoy their company; they make me feel even more welcome to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>PVC Pipes</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/03/26/pipes/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/03/26/pipes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/03/IMG_0002.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;PVC Pipes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe is pictured above setting up the PVC pipe to allow us to determine the amount of water that could be provided by the potential new source. We had to clear away sediment and even use a glove to prevent water from seeping through the mini-dam we built. We recorded the time it took to fill a Nalgene bottle to calculate the flow rate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Water Testing</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/03/25/water-testing/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/03/25/water-testing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/03/IMG_0001.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Water Testing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above picture shows the water quality testing procedure. The water samples from various sources were stored in plastic tubes until they were ready for testing. The second picture above shows the coliform and e-coli counting procedure.  After an incubation period we counted the number of colonies present in each plate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Local School in Chichimuch</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/03/24/local-school-in-chichimuch/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/03/24/local-school-in-chichimuch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2015/03/IMG_0003.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Local School in Chichimuch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today our team visited the local school in Chichimuch.  During our visit we ran tests on the filters in the school and gave a presentation to some of the kids.  In this picture you can see the team showing one of the classes a short animation in Spanish about sanitation and hygiene. This animation was created by a University of Illinois organization called SAWBO (Scientific Animations Without Borders) that makes various free animations with numerous translations of local languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photospheres</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/03/21/photospheres/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/03/21/photospheres</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Photospheres:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1430432009493!6m8!1m7!1stL8eIJ2A1uQAAAQfDObcAg!2m2!1d14.770522!2d-91.266238!3f185.74!4f12.780000000000001!5f0.7820865974627469&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1430432142548!6m8!1m7!1s5OHDbx8zIcUAAAQfDPZ4Vg!2m2!1d14.770957!2d-91.251484!3f188.98!4f-22.239999999999995!5f0.7820865974627469&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1430432161139!6m8!1m7!1sBvGhT6xUHx8AAAQfDObcAA!2m2!1d14.77313!2d-91.252913!3f355.78!4f-26.54!5f0.7820865974627469&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1430434161900!6m8!1m7!1sm4hrvXbRjoIAAAQfDObcAw!2m2!1d14.773366!2d-91.253035!3f355.34!4f8.170000000000002!5f0.7820865974627469&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1430434189190!6m8!1m7!1sgxHadx30THQAAAQfDPZ4Uw!2m2!1d14.76292!2d-91.250334!3f83.59!4f-11.599999999999994!5f0.7820865974627469&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://maps.google.com/maps?layer=c&amp;amp;panoid=0oqO-BbJnGoAAAQfDObcAQ&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;output=svembed&amp;amp;cbp=13%2C175.6252%2C%2C0%2C26&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Guatemala Trip</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/02/17/guatemala-trip/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/02/17/guatemala-trip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Photo set from the Guatemala Trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_0001.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_0002.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_7705.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_8015.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_7949.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/IMG_0003.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Guatemala Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing 2015 Board Members</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2015/01/19/introducing-2015-board/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2015/01/19/introducing-2015-board</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;president&quot;&gt;President&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayzvara Suntharalingam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vice-president&quot;&gt;Vice President&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda Sopkin, Arjun Kumar, Kevin Ger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;treasurer&quot;&gt;Treasurer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian Wu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-officers&quot;&gt;Information Officers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Dixon, Hunter Smith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;events-officer&quot;&gt;Events Officer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Lin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;webmaster&quot;&gt;Webmaster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Milla&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EWB Banquet</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/12/13/ewb-banquet/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/12/13/ewb-banquet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The annual year-end banquet and awards ceremony was held on the 10th of December at the University YMCA. Both members and mentors alike had the opportunity to reflect on our progress and accomplishments this past year. The upcoming board was introduced, outstanding members &amp;amp; project leads acknowledged, while our graduating seniors were given a farewell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Travel Panel</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/11/22/travel-panel/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/11/22/travel-panel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our general meeting was hosted on Tuesday November 18th at 6:00-7:00pm in MSEB100! We discussed about the general traveling process with regards to our international projects. Older members were able to share their personal experiences with newer members.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EWB National Conference</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/11/08/ewb-national-conference/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/11/08/ewb-national-conference</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The annual conference was hosted during the 31st October to 2nd November in Reston, Virginia! Participants managed to learn from informational sessions and insightful speakers regarding international development and service learning topics. Additionally, the conference provided participants with a great opportunity to network with corporate representatives, professionals and students alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Program Application</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/10/11/new-program-application/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/10/11/new-program-application</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our chapter is preparing to get involved with two additional projects that are both locally and globally orientated. Interested candidates that submitted applications were chosen through a rigorous selection process for both the domestic and international projects on offer. We wish the upcoming teams all the best in their preparations for the new projects!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Member Orientation</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/09/20/new-member-orientation/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/09/20/new-member-orientation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our chapter hosted an orientation session to integrate new members with various projects. We hope that newer members are able to adapt to our on-going projects and get exposed to important elements &amp;amp; skill sets needed to succeed in a project. Project leads coordinated hands-on activities to convey information on their respective projects and help new members transition smoothly!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Info Session</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/09/13/info-session/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/09/13/info-session</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two informational sessions were  hosted on the 9th and 10th of September respectively in DCL1320 to share about what we do as a chapter and how members could get involved in various international development projects available in our chapter. We were glad that affliated organizations were able to participate in the event as well to expose attendees to the opportunities beyond EWB!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assessment Trip</title>
   <link href="http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org///2014/08/01/assessment-trip/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ewb-usa-uiuc.org//2014/08/01/assessment-trip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0002.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our most recent assessment trip last August was extremely successful. During the trip, we surveyed the village households in order to gain a complete understanding of the people’s needs and expectations for this project. We also asked questions pertaining to the financial sustainability of the project. Unanimously, the people of the Likoko village said that they could afford the monthly utility bills that would come out of establishing an electric grid system. In addition to the house surveys, we created a Memorandum of Understanding and an Implementation Agreement that the village leaders agreed and signed. In these documents, the community leaders confirmed that they would be able to supply a 10% cash contribution towards the initial construction costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0001.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0003.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, during their trip, the project team met with the Mayor of Buea. He gave his blessing for the project and promised to supply government-run street lights for the municipality. Overall, there is an overwhelming support in the community for this project to go forward so we expect there to be high community involvement throughout the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0206.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/2014/08/IMG_0435.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Assessment Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also investigated financial considerations for the project during this trip. We were able to get price estimates for installing in-house wiring. We surveyed possible transmission line routes and determined an ideal path that would connect all of the Likoko households as well as four schools to the power line. We are currently working on cost estimates for constructing a transmission line along this route. Lastly, we investigated potential future projects such as health education and electrically powered water distribution, which could be our next steps after implementing the electrical grid system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
